synchronybank.com 2019-01-01

# Internet Privacy Policy | Synchrony Bank

Synchrony Bank is committed to protecting your privacy at all times.

Please read this Internet Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) carefully before using the Synchrony Bank (“Bank”) website (the “Site”). The Bank, a federal savings bank headquartered in Utah, is the owner of the Site, although software, hosting and other functions and content may be provided by the Bank’s service providers, affiliates or business partners. This Site is exclusively directed to, and intended for, legal residents of the United States who are adults of a capacity to contemplate and enter into a lawful contract for banking purposes. The Bank does not knowingly solicit information from, and does not knowingly market any products or services to, minors or non-U.S. residents. If you are under the age of 18, you are not permitted to set up an account through the Site, and do not enter your personal information.

This Policy, together with the Website Usage Agreement which is incorporated herein by reference and attached at the end of this Policy, describes the types of information we may collect from visitors to the Site, what we do with this information, and how visitors can update and control the use of information they provide on the Site. This Policy applies solely to information that visitors provide through this Site. This Policy does not apply to other data we collect, including data collected on other websites, such as separate websites operated by our affiliates or business partners, or information visitors may provide to us through unsolicited email or other means.

What personal information do we collect from you online, and how do we use it?

You can browse our Site without revealing any personal information. However, if you decide to open an account with the Bank, you will be asked to provide your personal and banking information through this Site in order to create and fund your account. (In that case, the information you provide will be subject to the Bank’s Privacy Notice.) To open an account, the information we require includes, but is not limited to:

  * Name, address, and phone number
  * Email address
  * Date of birth
  * Social Security Number
  * Other personal information used to verify your identity
  * The account number, routing number, and name of the financial institution where you currently have an account that you will use to fund your account(s) with the Bank
  * Username and password that you will create when registering for an account

Once you provide this information to us, you will not be able to delete it.

In addition, you may provide us with personal information when submitting a question or request through Contact Us. We use the information that you provide to us in order to:

  * Provide you with products or services you have requested
  * Service your account
  * Improve our services
  * Develop other products or services
  * Inform you about our other products or services and our service providers, affiliates, and business partners
  * Notify you about changes to our Site or to our services
  * Provide monthly statements

What information is collected from your computer?

When you visit our Site, our servers collect the name of the domain you used to access the Internet (such as Google.com), which pages on our Site you visited and when they were visited, your Internet browser type and platform, your IP address, the link that brought you to our Site and any links clicked within our Site. If your IP address is in or associated with a high risk location, we may require additional authentication including, but not limited to, inputting a one-time password to help prevent fraudulent transactions on your account. This information is collectedly anonymously, meaning that our servers do not collect your name or other personal information. This information may be used by us, our service providers, affiliates and business partners to measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views and other general statistics about the overall use of our Site. We also use this information to monitor Site performance and make the Site easier and more convenient to use.

In connection with the California Online Privacy Policy Protection Act we are advising you that we do not respond to browser do-not-track signals. All information on who we share your data with and your choices are discussed in this Internet Privacy Policy.

Do we use cookies?

Cookies are small pieces of data stored by your Internet browser on your computer's hard drive. If you visit our Site, a cookie is used to help us measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views and other statistics relating to our Site. This cookie by itself does not tell us your email address or who you are. If you decide to register online or request information, products or services from us, we may collect additional information to provide tailored offerings or content to you or to deliver such products and services. In this case, we use cookies to allow us to recognize you on subsequent visits enhance your online experience and make our provision of products and services more efficient. We do not use cookies to get data from your hard drive or to get your email address. You may set your Internet browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to prevent cookies from being sent. Please note, however, that by not accepting cookies, you may limit the functionality we can provide you when you visit our Site and your ability to access certain products and services we offer.

What information do we share?

When you provide information to us through our Site, we may share your information with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. These third parties are not necessarily related by common ownership or control with the Bank. These service providers are only authorized to use this information to perform services on our behalf, to perform services requested by you or your representatives, or to comply with legal requirements. Unless otherwise described in this Policy, we will use and share information that we collect from or about you in accordance with our Privacy Notice.

We also may aggregate statistics that we gather about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and services and provide these statistics to our service providers, affiliates and business partners in aggregate form. This information and these statistics, which do not contain any personal information, may be used by the Bank for its business purposes, including the offering of products or services, research, marketing or analyzing market trends, and other purposes consistent with applicable laws.

We may disclose your information: (i) where it is necessary for completing transfers; (ii) in order to verify the existence and condition of your account for a third party, such as a credit bureau or merchant; (iii) in order to comply with government agency or court orders; (iv) in the event that all or part of the Bank or all or part of its assets are acquired by, merged with, sold to, or otherwise disposed of to one or more third parties, as permitted by applicable law and regulations; (v) if you give us written permission; or (vi) as otherwise permitted or required by law.

How will we use your email address?

If you do not apply for an account, we will not request your email address and we will not attempt to contact you by email unless you submit an inquiry to “Contact Us” and provide your email address. If you begin but do not complete an account application, or if you complete your application but do not fund your new account, we may send a reminder email to ensure you are able to open your new account exactly as you wish. From time to time we may send you automatic and/or voluntary account alerts if you agree to receive email messages from us. We may also send you email to notify you about changes to our Site or service.

In addition to being able to call our customer service department, you may also email us through the Site. When you email us, your emails are stored within our system so that we may refer to previous emails from you as needed to properly address your questions. Except as provided in this Internet Privacy Policy, the information you provide to our customer service department is not shared with anyone without your consent.

At times, we conduct online surveys to better understand the needs, profiles and experience of our visitors. You will be given the option of not participating in such surveys.

Remember that this Policy only applies to this Site, so that if you have another account with us and/or with one of our affiliates, you may also receive emails regarding that other account.

What happens if you visit another website from our Site?

This Policy only applies to the use and disclosure of information we collect from visitors and customers online through our Site. Once you leave our Site, either by a link or by entering a new Internet address in your browser’s address window, we no longer have control over information security, and we are not responsible for the content, privacy practices or your use of other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of those other sites.

How do we protect your information?

Our goal is to protect the personal information you submit to us through this Site. We and our service providers have implemented technical and organizational measures designed to protect against loss or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the information you provide on our Site. We instruct our personnel with access to your personal information that such access must be used only in adherence with the principles set forth in this Policy and applicable laws, and for no other purpose. Personnel who misuse customer information are subject to disciplinary action. Finally, no security measures, however thorough, are perfect. Accordingly, we do not guarantee the security of the information you provide to us.

How can you help to protect your personal information?

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account username and password. We recommend that you choose a unique password for your account and that you do not use any password that you also use for any other accounts which may contain your sensitive information, such as financial accounts or email accounts. You agree to immediately notify the Bank of any unauthorized use of your password or account or any other breach of security. We will not be responsible or liable for any loss or damage arising from your failure to comply with this provision.

If you access our Site from a public or shared computer, it may be possible for other users to review your online history. For this reason, you should always close your browser window after you finish any online banking session, including visiting our Site. If you access our Site from a shared computer, you should never set the Internet options to remember or store user IDs or passwords. Also, you should never go to websites or follow web links that are unfamiliar or seem suspicious to you.

What if you are an international user?

This is a United States-based website that is subject to United States law. This Site is controlled, operated and administered by the Bank from its offices within the United States. This Policy is provided in accordance with and subject to applicable U.S. law. If you are accessing this Site using a computer that is located outside the United States, you are responsible to ensure that your Internet connection is secure and is not monitored, legally or otherwise, by any third party or jurisdiction. If you are unsure of the security of your international Internet access, you should refrain from accessing this Site until you have confirmed that your access is secure and not monitored.

If you decide to continue to access this Site from your location outside the United States, you hereby agree that your use of this Site is subject to this Policy and U.S. law and that you are responsible for complying with applicable laws in all jurisdictions that govern your use and access of this Site.

Our Right to Modify the Internet Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify or supplement this Policy at any time and without prior notice. If we make any material change to the Policy, we will update our Site to include such changes. We recommend that you review this Policy regularly for changes.

Making Sure Your Information is Accurate

Keeping your account information accurate and up to date is very important. If your account information is incomplete, inaccurate or not current, please contact Customer Service or write to us at the telephone numbers or appropriate address for changes listed on your online account statements, records, online or other account materials.

Your Consent

By proceeding to use this Site and the applications and features thereon, you hereby acknowledge and provide your consent for the Bank and its service providers, affiliates and business partners, domiciled in the United States or internationally, to collect and use your information, and to transfer and store your information across national boundaries.

If you have any questions about this Policy, you can contact us by calling 1-866-226-5638.

FDIC insurance is up to $250,000 per depositor, per insured bank, for each ownership category. Identity Theft Resolution Services are provided by CyberScout™.
